{
  "lessonId": "lesson17",
  "lessonTitle": "Урок 17",
  "lessonDescription": "Спеціальні запитання у Present Simple",
  "lessonURL": "",
  "lessonItems": [
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "What / When / Where / Who / Whose / Which / Why / How + <b>AM / ARE / IS</b> + subject + other words",
      "startTime": "1:26"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Хто є ти?",
      "answer":   "Who are you?",
      "startTime": "1:46"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Де вона? Де є вона?",
      "answer":   "Where is she?",
      "startTime": "1:55"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>how old</b> скільки років",
      "startTime": "1:03"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Скільки йому років?",
      "answer":   "How old is he?",
      "startTime": "2:09"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Скільки років твоєму собаці?",
      "answer":   "How old is your dog?",
      "startTime": "2:19"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Чий друг є ти?",
      "answer":   "Whose friend are you?",
      "startTime": "2:29"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Що це?",
      "answer":   [
        "What is this?",
        "What's this?"
      ],
      "startTime": "2:37"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>now</b> /naʊ/ зараз",
      "startTime": "2:53"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Який день зараз?",
      "answer":   "What day is it now?",
      "startTime": "2:56"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Коли твій день народження?",
      "answer":   "When is your birthday?",
      "startTime": "3:04"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Чому вони тут?",
      "answer":   "Why are they here?",
      "startTime": "3:18"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Чия це парасолька?",
      "answer":   "Whose umbrella is it?",
      "startTime": "3:31"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Де я?",
      "answer":   "Where am I?",
      "startTime": "4:20"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Яке твоє хобі?",
      "answer":   "What is your hobby?",
      "startTime": "4:36"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Де твоє домашнє завдання?",
      "answer":   [
        "Where is your homework?",
        "Where's your homework?"
      ],
      "startTime": "4:45"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>flight</b> /flaɪt/ політ, рейс",
      "startTime": "5:00"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Коли твій рейс?",
      "answer":   "When is your flight?",
      "startTime": "5:02"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Як справи?",
      "answer":   "How are you?",
      "startTime": "5:10"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>How are you? How is it going? How's it going?</b> Як справи?",
      "startTime": "5:20"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>yours</b> /jɔː(ɹ)z/ твій. Вживається в кінці питання, коли нема іменників.",
      "startTime": "5:55"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Який будинок є твій?",
      "answer":   "Which house is yours?",
      "startTime": "6:01"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>exam</b> /ɪɡˈzæm/ екзамен",
      "startTime": "6:47"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Коли є наші екзамени?",
      "answer":   "When are our exams?",
      "startTime": "6:49"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Яка машина є його?",
      "answer":   "Which car is his?",
      "startTime": "6:59"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>job</b> /d͡ʒɑb/ робота",
      "startTime": "7:42"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>mine</b> /maɪn/ мій, моє",
      "startTime": "7:48"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Яка робота є моя?",
      "answer":   "Which job is mine?",
      "startTime": "8:03"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>successful</b> /səkˈsɛsfl̩/ успішний",
      "startTime": "8:54"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Хто є успішний?",
      "answer":   "Who is successful?",
      "startTime": "8:57"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Де є офіс?",
      "answer":   "Where is the office?",
      "startTime": "9:13"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Котра година?",
      "answer":   "What time is it?",
      "startTime": "9:20"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>far</b> /fɑː/ далеко",
      "startTime": "9:28"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Як далеко є це?",
      "answer":   "How far is it?",
      "startTime": "9:37"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Як далеко є супермаркет?",
      "answer":   "How far is a supermarket?",
      "startTime": "9:45"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Чому я?",
      "answer":   "Why am I?",
      "startTime": "9:52"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>meeting</b> /ˈmiːtɪŋ/ зустріч, збори",
      "startTime": "9:58"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Коли є зустріч?",
      "answer":   "When is the meeting?",
      "startTime": "10:00"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Як тебе звати?",
      "answer":   "What is your name?",
      "startTime": "10:09"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Де є ресторан?",
      "answer":   "Where is the restaurant?",
      "startTime": "10:15"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Скільки років Карлу (Karl)?",
      "answer":   "How old is Karl?",
      "startTime": "10:22"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Який це фільм?",
      "answer":   "What movie is it?",
      "startTime": "11:27"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Чому ти втомлений сьогодні?",
      "answer":   "Why are you tired today?",
      "startTime": "11:37"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Чому вона голодна?",
      "answer":   "Why is she hungry?",
      "startTime": "11:44"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Яка столиця Іспанії (Spain)?",
      "answer":   "What is the capital of Spain?",
      "startTime": "11:52"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>favourite</b> /ˈfeɪv.ɹɪt/ улюблений",
      "startTime": "12:06"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>activity</b> /ækˈtɪ.vɪ.ti/ активність, діяльність",
      "startTime": "12:07"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Які їх улюблені види діяльності?",
      "answer":   "What are their favourite activities?",
      "startTime": "12:09"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Коли твоє англійське заняття?",
      "answer":   [
        "When is your English class?",
        "When is your English lesson?"
      ]
      "startTime": "12:25"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Звідки він?",
      "answer":   "Where is he from?",
      "startTime": "12:39"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Якою є робота Рут (Ruth)?",
      "answer":   "What is Ruth's job?",
      "startTime": "13:20"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "name + <b>'s</b> вказує на належність комусь",
      "startTime": "13:41"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Звідки ти?",
      "answer":   "Where are you from?",
      "startTime": "14:00"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>location</b> /loʊˈkeɪʃən/ розташування",
      "startTime": "14:15"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Яке місцезнаходження компанії твого батька?",
      "answer":   "What is the location of your dad's company?",
      "startTime": "14:17"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Хто такий Бред Пітт (Brad Pitt)?",
      "answer":   "Who is Brad Pitt?",
      "startTime": "15:03"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>Thames</b> /tɛmz/ Темза",
      "startTime": "15:19"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "Перед назвою річки завжди ставиться the",
      "startTime": "15:26"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Що таке Темза (Thames)?",
      "answer":   "What is the Thames?",
      "startTime": "15:31"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Коли поп концерт?",
      "answer":   "When is the pop concert?",
      "startTime": "15:41"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Хто я?",
      "answer":   "Who am I?",
      "startTime": "15:48"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Де Алабама (Alabama)?",
      "answer":   "Where is Alabama?",
      "startTime": "15:54"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Чому твоя маленька сестра тут?",
      "answer":   "Why is your little sister here?",
      "startTime": "16:01"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>backpack</b> /ˈbæk.pæk/ рюкзак",
      "startTime": "16:13"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Де твій рюкзак?",
      "answer":   "Where is your backpack?",
      "startTime": "16:26"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>island</b> /ˈaɪ̯lənd/ острів",
      "startTime": "16:36"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Чий це острів?",
      "answer":   "Whose island is this?",
      "startTime": "16:44"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>chair</b> /t͡ʃɛə(ɹ)/ стілець",
      "startTime": "17:03"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Який це стілець?",
      "answer":   [
        "Which chair is it?",
        "What chair is it?"
      ],
      "startTime": "17:07"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>sea</b> /siː/ море",
      "startTime": "17:33"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Чому діти у морі?",
      "answer":   "Why are the children in the sea?",
      "startTime": "17:47"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Хто ці люди?",
      "answer":   "Who are these people?",
      "startTime": "18:28"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>upstairs</b> /ˈʌpˌstɛɹz/ вгорі,верхній поверх",
      "startTime": "19:00"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Чому ти нагорі?",
      "answer":   "Why are you upstairs?",
      "startTime": "19:10"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>downstairs</b> /daʊnˈstɛɹz/ внизу",
      "startTime": "19:22"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Чому він внизу?",
      "answer":   "Why is he downstairs?",
      "startTime": "19:32"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>passport</b> /ˈpɑːspɔːt/ паспорт",
      "startTime": "19:37"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Де твій паспорт?",
      "answer":   "Where is your passport?",
      "startTime": "19:39"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Які це мови?",
      "answer":   "What languages are these?",
      "startTime": "19:52"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Які твої вміння?",
      "answer":   "What are your skills?",
      "startTime": "20:21"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Скільки там дерев?",
      "answer":   "How many trees are there?",
      "startTime": "20:27"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Скільки це? Скільки це коштує?",
      "answer":   "How much is it?",
      "startTime": "21:00"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>goal</b> /ɡɔʊl/ ціль, мета",
      "startTime": "21:26"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Яка мета твого життя?",
      "answer":   "What is the goal of your life?",
      "startTime": "21:35"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "point",
      "itemText": "<b>space</b> /speɪs/ простір, космос",
      "startTime": "21:47"
    },
    {
      "itemType": "question",
      "question": "Що є твоїм життєвим простором?",
      "answer":   "What is your life space?",
      "startTime": "21:57"
    }
  ]
}
